Over the next 12 months, the biggest IPOs of 2024 and 2025 are going to happen on the LSE and a new exchange in America.
Specifically, the biggest IPO of 2024 is going to happen on the LSE from Shien, the company that's gone up from $30 to $42 billion.
Next year, it'll probably be $60 billion. It'll probably be the biggest apparel company in the world that's growing that fast and is that profitable.
And similar to Nvidia, it doesn't have any actual assets.
It's just essentially AI or software figuring out how to figure out a way to get you your stuff more inexpensively.
And then the biggest IPO of 2025 will be SpaceX on the new Texas exchange.
So we're about to see what I would loosely call exchange wars and Raspberry Pi, which decided to go public on the LSE last week.
This is a cool little company actually chose the LSE.
So the LSE is no longer going to be seen as the exchange of last choice.
It's going to be something where cool companies go public.
That is going to add $5 or $10 billion in market cap to Shien, which people see as going to the LSE only because they have to.
And then you can bet Elon Musk is in the background on this new Texas exchange.
And the first, the biggest IPO of 2025 will be SpaceX on the new Texas exchange.