It's 1800 hours Eastern Standard Time.
Welcome.
My name is Scott Galloway, Professor of Marketing at NYU Stern and the founder of Section 4,
and we appreciate your time tonight.
Over the course of the next 40 to 50 minutes, we're going to be talking about our predictions
for 2021.
Some disclosure right up front.
I get this wrong all the time.
And as Eisenhower said, plans are useless, but planning is invaluable.
And I think the same about predictions.
Predictions are somewhat worthless, but predicting is invaluable, as hopefully this catalyzes
some discussion within your own organization that helps you develop economic security for
you and your family.
So with that, we're going to revisit our predictions from 2020, keep a scorecard, try and hold
ourselves accountable.
Then we're going to bust into our predictions for the next 12 months.
We'll do a summary.
We'll open it up to Q&A.
And then we're going to close on some thoughts on prosperity versus progress.
Quick add, the firm I work for, Section 4, launches Sprints.
In sum, our objective is to offer elite marketing and strategy business school electives at
one tenth the price.
Every course we have offered has sold out.
Our latest course, Product Strategy, with Professor Adam Alter, a colleague of mine
at NYU Stern, kicks off in January, is sold out.
I will then be teaching the next two sprints, Brand kicking off in February and Strategy
kicking off in March.
And then also in March, we'll have Platform Strategy with Kellogg Professor of Strategy
and Marketing, Mohan Saini, kicking off in March.
Again, every one of our courses has sold out.
If you cannot afford the fee, please reach out.
And we give away approximately 10% of all enrollments are for scholarships.
Okay, if you want to ask a question towards the end of this session, please upvote your
favorite questions, submit a question on the Q&A panel, and then for a greater chance of
getting it answered, we'll pick the ones that are upvoted.
We'll put you on our virtual stage and you will get the opportunity to ask a question.
What is real?
Some disclosures.
I have purchased stock in this year or own stock in the following companies.
Some of them are private, some of them are public.
So if I sound like I'm talking my own book, I am.
But I'd like to think I'm putting my money where my mouth is.
And I'm not just saying this, I'm actually I have some, if you will, some skin in the
game.
So let's revisit 2020.
Prediction, the Democratic nominee would be Bloomberg or Buttigieg.
Got that wrong.
Enough said.
I know that's you.
But I'm going to miss the I had not seen the background.
This is quite nice.
I'm going to miss the misogyny, the bigotry and the general ass or head up your assery
stupidity of the last four years.
I'm going to miss that.
But anyways, welcome Biden and Harris.
Uber exits food delivery.
We got that wrong.
As a matter of fact, they doubled down on food delivery, acquired Postmates.
And this, to be fair, I'm not a big fan of Uber.
I think it's part of the menace economy.
We figured out a way to take advantage of a permanent underclass new software to circumvent
minimum wage laws.
But distinct to that, you have to give the management team kudos for pivoting and taking
advantage of the COVID-19 pandemic and moving into food delivery, which has surged as ride
hailing has declined.
And you can see that this probably saved Uber's market capitalization.
You got to think that Uber would be struggling right now.
Have they not made this acquisition?
For 24 months, FedEx is acquired or down 30% as a prediction I made.
Amazon is now spending more money on fulfillment than FedEx or Walmart and has a clean sheet
design and it's just executing better.
And I thought this was going to primarily be the beginning of the end for FedEx.
And I thought this was going really well.
And then COVID came along and distinct of all the death, disease and disability, it's
messed with my predictions, which is really the tragedy here.
And as you can tell, FedEx has surged.
Good for them.
Their shipping volumes are up.
They're going to play a critical role in the distribution of the vaccine.
Way to go, guys.
Amazon will be the fastest growing health care company in the world by 2025.
I'm going to say that we have gotten this right or we are getting it right.
Amazon has piloted several health care initiatives on its own employees and has all the assets
to create a corpus of your digital health care system, specifically a wearable that
tracks a lot of data, including your body mass index, your movement, what foods you
order, your purchase history, your demographics, your wealth, whether you're in a monogamous
relationship, your zip code, all the actuarial inputs you would need to build an entire vision
or image of your digital health.
And they'll be able to not only offer you products and services and a diet, but get
off their heels and onto their toes from a health care standpoint and perhaps offer
you insurance, diagnostics or even primary care over smartphones or smart speakers.
I believe that the relationship Amazon has with 82 percent of American households, and
by the way, that's the most trusted relationship in the United States between a corporation
and a company, that health care is a natural fit.
And it is clear they are lining up their tanks, their planes and their artillery at the border
to go after what is the most disruptible business in the world, specifically the 17 percent
of US GDP or the four, the three to four trillion dollar business that is health care.
The party stops in 2020.
We predicted this in December after basically an 11 year bull run and we see a 20 percent
correction in the Dow.
Boom, that happened.
It's also had a vicious rip back, but we did have that decline.
I'm going to give us a win there.
Private company valuations will continue to decline.
We're seeing declines.
There are some big winners, but on the whole, there have been more down rounds, approximately
double the number of down rounds in 2020 than there had been in previous years.
Vision Fund 2 does not happen.
Remember WeWork, doesn't that just seem cute now?
Doesn't that just seem kind of fun, the whole SoftBank WeWork fiasco?
Well, we were right here.
This thing has not worked from the start.
Take somebody who conflates the luckiest investment in the world, 10 million, 50 million into
Alibaba for a hundred million dollar return and they start believing they're a genius
and regression of the mean and karma has a way of catching up to you and Vision Fund
2 is not going to happen.
In 2020, Airbnb becomes more valuable than Uber.
You might say, well, that's obvious.
Well, it wasn't obvious at the time when we made the prediction, when we made the prediction,
Airbnb's value was 30 billion and went to 18.
And at the same time, Uber's valuation was approximately double.
So we said, OK, these things are going to revert.
Where are we now?
They're primarily equal.
And that is because of the pandemic, because of a great move around acquiring a ride
hailing, excuse me, a delivery company, Uber stock has surged, but it hasn't surged as
much as Airbnb and Airbnb is on the precipice of eclipsing Uber's market capitalization.
As a matter of fact, it may have happened today.
Why is Airbnb such an incredible gangster company?
It is a platform.
It has incredible moats around network effects.
And as we're seeing, it is accelerating 115% up on the first day of the IPO.
Twitter attracts an activist investor or is acquired.
I wrote a letter to the board of Twitter management or to the board of directors.
Interesting, I did not hear back.
They did not write the dog back.
And to be blunt, I felt that Twitter having a part time CEO is on the verge of comical.
I've been on several public company boards and dozens of private boards, and I've never
met a CEO who can manage two firms at the same time.
So maybe Dorsey has some superpower I'm not aware of.
And if Twitter moves just one, three, 10% of its revenue to a subscription model, I
believe that the stock would surge.
And as a result, Elliot, one of the largest hedge funds in the world, read my letter and
basically showed up and signed it with a $1 billion pen, got three seats on the board,
which means that the board knew that they were outgunned and they gave up board seats
incredibly, incredibly fast.
The stock has continued to go up and I believe that the stock will hit $70 per share if the
board continues to pull its head out of its ass and fires the part time CEO, moves him
up to chairman so he can have peace with dignity and shows any pulse around subscription.
I think that's going to happen this year.
By the way, management teams and boards don't put out letters confirming or validating or
reinforcing the CEO's job unless they're about to fire him and he's looking for peace with
honor or a graceful exit.
We have here an absentee CEO.
This is a number of words spoken in the earnings call by the Twitter CEO versus the other CEOs.
Now is he just an introvert?
Earnings calls aren't silent retreats.
This is an opportunity for you to outline your vision and he has no vision because in
the afternoon he is at another company that represents 90% of his wealth.
What do we also have here with our part time CEO?
We have part time revenue growth.
Look at the usage patterns there up.
To be clear, this is a fantastic product.
Yet, yet the revenue growth does not match their user growth.
Whereas at the other social media firms, Snap and Facebook, revenue growth is outpacing
user growth.
What is wrong with this movie?
When Dorsey speaks, the stock drops.
This guy opens his mouth and people say, wow, great product, great opportunity, shitty part
time CEO and every time he speaks, he reinforces our instincts here.
Let's sell the stock.
Quibi will be the worst performing unicorn in 2020.
And the tough thing about predictions is when you get them right, they seem obvious in retrospect.
But a little a little 411 on when we made this prediction, we made it a long time ago
before they even launched.
As a matter of fact, the CFO of the company was a Stern grad called me and said, hey,
boss, can you not dance on our grave before we've been birded?
You're not helping.
So I quieted the hell down.
But not after I said this thing made absolutely no sense.
And look at the headlines and the excitement coming out of the gates for Quibi.
Oh, my God, quick bites.
It's going to be awesome.
Right. They secured 100 million dollars of ad commitments ahead of launch.
Remember all the excitement about the new judge, Judy.
Right. I wrote this post in February saying this thing made absolutely no sense.
And what skill, what vision did we bring to the party here?
Math simply put for every billion dollars in content that you get from Apple,
they only charge you 83 cents a month.
Netflix gives you a billion dollars in content in exchange for 81 cents a month.
And guess what?
Quibi thought by slicing stuff up into three or five or seven minute segments
that they could charge you eight bucks for every billion dollars in content.
That just made no sense.
They showed up to a squirt.
They showed up to a howitzer fight with a squirt gun.
This thing just right out of the gates was a terrible value proposition.
They were outgunned.
What do you know? What do you know?
Just after six months.
By the way, if you're working at Quibi, the best thing that can happen to you is success.
The second best thing that can happen is quick failure.
So the second best thing happened to the folks at Quibi and the people who work there.
Whereas failing over decades or a decade, like I did a red envelope, that shit hurts.
That shit hurts. So failing fast.
Don't feel sorry for them. They are just fine.
Apple goes full Rundle and hits 200 bucks a share.
That's the prediction here.
That's the prediction. Why? Why?
Because we predicted they would go full Rundle back in October.
What I believe will be one of the most powerful recurring revenue bundles,
and that is the Apple Rundle.
This bundle of goods will likely include Apple TV Plus and Apple Music, which is gangster.
But in my view, in my view, they should go they should go big time
and include Arcade, Apple News Plus and Apple Care Plus.
Don't you love listening to me as you're watching me?
That's like shavings of shit on a shit salad. Sorry about that.
Expect more. Anyways, look what's happening here.
Look what's happening.
Apple has had anemic growth both on the top line and the bottom line,
yet its stock price has accelerated. Why?
Why? Excuse me for my Senator Rubio, our senior senator,
whose testicles have not descended yet and has shown an extraordinary lack of leadership,
an extraordinary lack of leadership.
Anyways, here's to you, Senator Rubio.
That's good Italian overpriced ecologically or environmentally unfriendly water.
OK, OK.
So how is our stock price increased three and a half fold on a mild increase
in top line revenue and bottom line revenue?
Simple. A move to a recurring revenue bundle that got from nine percent recurring revenue
five years ago to almost 24 percent.
My guess is they like when they get their lips around the crack pipe
of shareholder growth at the hands of the most accretive action in business history.
Moving to a recurring revenue bundle, as we call it, as we call it, the rundle.
When they go full rundle, this is the most accretive action in business history.
And you need to be a CEO who not only thinks about top line and bottom line,
but your business model and moving into a monogamous relationship with your
consumer set. Apple took 42 years, 42 years to get to a trillion dollars.
And then it took five months to get to two trillion on the back of a recurring revenue
bundle. Apple is going full rundle in 2021.
What does that mean?
They're going to take their B League, Joey Bagadonis, Bad News Bears
existing rundle, right there, Apple won.
And they're going to add in this and they're going to add in the watch
and they're going to add in the AirPod Pros and they're going to add in the iPad.
You know, the ship we love Apple for.
And they will say to the billion wealthiest people on the planet,
iOS users, if you come in with us, if you establish a monogamous relationship
at 50, 100, 200 bucks a month, you get all of this early.
You get it preloaded.
The biggest mistake, the biggest mistake we make as marketers
and Apple has realized this, who's probably the best marketer in the world,
is that choice is not a good thing.
Choice is a bad thing. Choice is a tax. What do we want?
We don't want more choice. We want fewer choices.
We just want to be more confident.
And the choice is presented.
They just peel off 10 percent of the people signaling, have sex with me.
I'm a better storyteller. I'm a baller. I make money.
You should have kids with me.
Your kids are more likely to survive if you have sex with me and we procreate
than if you have sex with someone who has an Android device.
True story, true story.
So if they just get 10 percent of their iOS base, that's 100 million people
and 100 bucks a month, they have 10 billion dollars a month in recurring revenue.
Boom, 200 dollars a share.
Boom, three trillion dollar market capitalization.
It's coming. Our prediction.
We said that Disney would win round one of the streaming wars.
And you say, well, that's obvious.
Well, it was an obvious back when we said that.
This is where Disney was. The Disney Channel had not worked.
People had a head start on them. People had more capital.
This is where we were when we made this prediction.
And then what happened a year later?
Disney has absolutely sprinted out.
We're talking like steroid Ben Johnson out of the blocks here.
It has been inspiring both on an Emmy side and on a new subscriber side.
We also predicted.
That Shopify and Roku would be the new kids on the block,
that these companies were coming into their own
and would achieve an altitude or an elevation they hadn't done yet.
And oh, my gosh, look at these two.
Look at these two. We're so proud. We're so proud.
Canada. Oh, my gosh.
It's good to see Canada.
Can you imagine that Canada right now says, are we in an apartment
living above a meth lab called America?
Anyway, anyway, different talk show of one hundred and sixty and one hundred
and ninety five percent.
Shopify now worth more than FedEx, the largest mall operator, Simon
and Nordstrom. And look at these metrics around Roku.
Oh, my gosh, Roku.
I don't really know what Roku does.
I just know that they are killing it.
We said that TikTok and Microsoft was a total head fake.
And there was no way this would happen. Why?
Because distinctive what the current administration would like to believe,
we are a nation of laws.
We're also a nation of immigrants.
Anyways, 50 percent of PhDs in the US immigrants.
Hello. Hello.
70 percent of the NASDAQ by dollar volume run by first
and second generation immigrant.
I know. I know.
Our team gets the first round draft choice from every team in the nation.
But we don't want that.
We want to be xenophobes and really fucking weird and say to everyone,
no, we don't want the best people in the world.
We're going to be strange bigots.
Well, guess what?
We're a nation of laws and distinctive.
The current administration deciding to slice up and fork up
the corporate world, distinctive Microsoft going for this bait.
What idiots? Did you really think this was going to happen?
Did you really think this was going to happen?
We predicted it wouldn't. And we were right.
This made absolutely no sense whatsoever.
Oracle didn't win either.
They've just become a minority investor. Why?
Because she's in charge here.
China co-ops is an autocracy and has control over all of these firms.
By the way, TikTok is in fact a security risk.
And there is no reason that these firms, Chinese firms,
should have unfettered access to our markets if we don't have access to theirs.
But unilateralist, stupid, 140 character decisions were not sustainable.
Let's talk about this year.
Let's talk about 2021.
OK, first prediction in the face of antitrust,
Facebook stock increases and Amazon spins.
Have you noticed the distinct of this horrible crime against humanity
that the FTC actually wants to break up Facebook, as does any other
lawmaker that sees their eyes on the on the governor's mansion
who's an AG right now.
And what do you know? Facebook stock didn't move.
As a matter of fact, we've known this is coming for about three months.
And Facebook stock continues to accelerate.
In addition, there are now two points on the line of antitrust.
Two points. The first was the DOJ's action against Google.
The second was the FTC and the AG's against Facebook.
Who's third? Who's third?
It's going to be that company in Seattle.
But Bezos is smarter and probably more ego driven than any of the rest of us.
Why? Because he's my agent.
He's having the mother of all midlife crises.
By the way, I can relate to this because I'm in the midst of a midlife crisis.
That's the bad news.
The good news is I believe I'm going to grow out of it in about 40 or 50 years.
Anyways, anyways, there's no one who's going to tell Bezos to break up.
So he's going to say, no, I'm breaking up with you.
And he's going to spend AWS and AWS will be the most valuable company by 2025.
By using its vast rows of data and money,
Facebook has squashed or hindered what the company perceived to be potential threats.
The bottom line is they have shown up and said join or die.
But more than that, more than that, what what what could have what's happening?
That's the problem with innovation suppression.
When antitrust, when the DOJ has been asleep for 20 years,
we don't know what could have happened with WhatsApp.
I believe that WhatsApp might have gone into video or collaboration.
You think WhatsApp would have sat by and let teams or let Slack or let Zoom
developed into the companies they are.
I believe WhatsApp would be worth more right now and will be worth more
when it's an independent company.
But however, the sociopath and his lipstick on cancer
are lining troops up at the border.
Almost a third of lawyers at Facebook have been hired in the last 24 months.
He is not going to go down without a fight.
But oh, my brothers, he is going to go down.
And my sisters, the whole is less than the sum of its parts here.
As a split up firm similar to John D.
Rockefeller Rockefeller, when they took Standard Oil and split it into 34 companies,
Mark Zuckerberg will get wealthy here.
As a matter of fact, every stakeholder benefits in a breakup.
Shareholders, the tax base, VC backed companies, the employees who have more options.
Competition is a wonderful thing.
The only the only person who doesn't win is the CEO who wants to sit on the iron
throne of all seven realms, not just be king of the north.
Break this shit up.
AWS, the most valuable company in the world that is spun prophylactically by Bezos.
The great dispersion. Big theme here.
Big theme here. We've been talking about COVID-19 be more of an accelerant
than a change agent.
What is the real trend here, though? It's dispersion.
And that is value.
The core value a company offers is being dispersed to the end consumer
and skipping the traditional channels of distribution, be they stores,
be they movie theaters, be they traditional sales channels.
And I think this is arguably the biggest trend in business
and will create the most shareholder value.
We've had globalization, we've had digitization, and we have now dispersion.
And that's the theme of our predictions.
The ability to distribute products and services over a wide area
and where and when they are needed most, removing unnecessary friction and costs.
First big trend, dispersion of headquarters, right?
If you want to hear denial, get someone who owns an office building
at a movie theater in the same room.
Oh, people can't wait to get work back to work.
No, they can't. People can wait.
There is a cohort that wants to go back to work,
specifically young people looking for mentors, friends and mates.
A third of people meet their mate at work.
By the way, that's not necessarily a bad thing.
Different talk show.
However, we're going to see a dispersion of headquarters to residential,
specifically commercial real estate is going to move to residential.
We're also going to see a Renaissance and co-working.
I'm not a big fan of WeWork, but we're going to see co-working pop up again.
Why? Because most people are still working from home.
And even when they return, they're going to be used to having the flexibility
to stay at home, which will absolutely decrease
the cost of the building.
And we're going to see a need for a renewed need for co-working space.
Just look at San Francisco.
Co-working space to a certain level takes out the volatility
of both the cost on the demand and the supply side of commercial real estate.
In just 12 months, this is crazy.
San Francisco registered its lowest vacancy rate ever commercially
and then its highest.
That's what a pandemic will do to you.
We're also seeing a lot of people are increased number of searches,
Google searches for co-working, and we see a lot of firms
who are permanently adopting a work from home option.
Young people more than anyone want to be in offices.
You're seeing Facebook and Google and Amazon double down on urban real estate.
Huge leases signed in New York because they realize the key to their business,
the secret sauce is a double E 25 year old out of Dartmouth.
And she wants to spend a couple of years in New York.
And they're building these Xanadu like campuses for the cohorts,
specifically young people that want to come back to the office.
Prediction Airbnb will be bigger than the top five hotel chains combined
and hits $200 a share in some.
This is the strongest brand in the history of hospitality.
Look at the number of searches for any city when you're looking for a hotel room.
They dwarf every other search for hospitality combined.
Nobody's searching for a hotel room.
Every other search for hospitality combined.
Nobody says, oh, I got an Expedia in San Francisco.
Oh, I decided to get a booking.com on my business trip.
No one says that this is the strongest, biggest, deepest brand
in the history of hospitality or travel.
Seven million rooms more than the biggest players combined.
And also also a true tech company that has a greater percentage of their employees
are actual technologists or engineers greater than Amazon, Lyft or Uber.
We have a juggernaut here.
We have a juggernaut.
I predicted that this thing would be worth $100 billion in the IPO.
I was wrong.
It was worth 90, but it's worth more.
Look at how much it's worth right now or will be worth.
I believe it's going to be $120 billion by the end of the year,
which puts it at $200 a share.
I believe Restoration Hardware and Sonos will reach $1,000 and $40 a share respectively.
Why?
Because some of that trillions of dollars in commercial real estate
is going to disperse into the home and there just aren't that many good brands in the home.
Remember when you looked at a million or $2 million home and they bragged that they had a subzero freezer.
So a $2,500 item was being used to sell a million dollar home.
Well, Sonos and Restoration Hardware are two of the best brands in a sector that is about to absorb a trillion dollars
in unexpected stakeholder value and capital.
We've seen their stock prices increase, but it's just getting started in my view.
Disclosure. I don't know Sonos.
I don't own Sonos or Restoration Hardware.
And you're going to see these companies rocket.
Again, permanent, permanent demand destruction across a $10 to $12 trillion asset class.
And where is that money going to go?
It's going to go into residential.
Who else here has realized, well, that carpet looks really shitty or maybe I need a nicer apartment
or maybe it's time I put in drapes or I would like, I don't know,
it smells kind of funny in here.
I'm going to make it nicer.
That is what everyone is thinking in every house across America.
Plywood costs and residential real estate have hit all time highs and we're just getting started.
Why else?
We spent 17% of our budget on transportation.
We're not commuting as much.
What are we going to do with that money?
We're going to put it where we're not commuting from specifically our homes.
What does this mean?
The great dispersion of HQ to residential is going to be amazing for the brands on top of the x-axis here
and it's going to be an incredible shedding of value from some of the companies below the x-axis here.
Apple acquires Peloton.
That's right.
There has never been a brand that better fits to another brand than Peloton does to Apple.
Why?
There's a dispersion of the sweat of the industrial sweat complex to the home.
Simply put, gyms are dying.
There will be a mild resurgence.
They will still exist, but we're going to lose somewhere between 10 and 30% of that value of gyms.
Where's it going to go?
Into your garage and into different types of weights.
Look at what's happened to work at home equipment.
It is absolutely surged.
Peloton.
It's better to be lucky than good.
Peloton is both and you're going to see Apple come in and decide, I know, I know we want connected fitness.
We want connected fitness in this incredible company that has Apple like brand, Apple like margins.
And has a market capitalization of 32 billion dollars, which is crazy.
Maybe overvalued.
Maybe not.
Was Jet.com worth 3 billion dollars?
No.
Was it worth 10 billion dollars?
Probably to Walmart.
Yes.
Is Peloton worth 33 billion dollars?
I don't know.
Is it worth more than that to Apple?
Yes.
Apple has a 2 trillion dollar market capitalization.
That means that they pay a 30% premium and pay 40 billion.
That's a 2% dilution to acquire connected fitness in the home.
And what does that mean?
They get more and more of the all-important attention graph.
And that's what they are all trying to do.
They're all trying to be the access code, the operating system for our digital lives.
And this would be a baller move that increases anywhere from 30 to 60 minutes a day.
The amount of time you are staring at iOS.
Dispersion of retail.
First it went to warehouses in your doorstep.
Now it's moving to our phones and our tablets.
There'll be big acquisitions by Shopify and or Zoom.
These stocks are so rich.
This currency is so incredibly inflated.
I'm not sure I'd say overvalued because they're incredible performers,
but they are going to go shopping.
They are going to go shopping.
We haven't seen anything like this.
Good for them.
Shopify a 41 fold since in the last five years.
That gives me the ability and the need to go buy real EBITDA.
We've also seen incredible acceleration in the GMV they manage,
but they haven't made any acquisitions.
I expect they will make an enormous acquisition in 2021.
The stock performance, obviously extraordinary here of Zoom.
113 billion.
I am less bullish on Zoom.
I do not think it is as sustainable.
I believe that Zoom will either acquire or merge with a big, big company in 2021.
And the real interesting thing here, Zoom could be the AOL of 2021.
Why? Why?
They are up against.
They think they're a great white shark.
They think they're the badass of the ocean, but the apex predator simply put an orca,
which is smarter that is Microsoft with Teams and Salesforce with Slack might show up
and offer video and eat their lunch.
I think Zoom is very vulnerable and this 113 billion dollar market capitalization is
likely inflated.
They will recognize this and try and pull a Steve Case and merge with a traditional
big EBITDA company, maybe another Telco.
And I believe that merger will likely go down in history as one of the worst mergers
or acquisitions in history.
Zoom either has to buy their way out of this or sell.
This is not sustainable.
They are playing with giants and the giant is about to smack them hard.
They need to either hook up with an Atlassian, develop some sort of suite here,
but as a standalone entity, they are like single title publishing.
They are vulnerable.
What would be an interesting acquisition or an interesting merger?
Zoom and WhatsApp, which will be spun whether Zuckerberg likes it or not.
There will be a for sale of WhatsApp.
The dispersion of creativity.
Get the traditional gatekeepers out of the way.
An example, Etsy, which I think is just inspiring.
I would have thought they would have gotten run over by Amazon, but anyway, it's good for them.
Roblox will triple in value.
This is an incredible company that actually gives a good goddamn about safety in children.
It has a flywheel effect that helps people, helps creators do incredible games for kids.
Over a third of their revenues goes out to their creators.
Over 50% of kids in the US under the age of 16 have been on Roblox in the last 30 days.
This is arguably the most influential company in history as it relates to children.
And at the same time, they recognize how important this is.
So in their S1, they mentioned safety 60 times.
They mentioned parental six times, right?
This is what we had hoped that Facebook would have been had it not been run by a sociopath.
Roblox is the social media company we all wanted.
It is a true platform.
By the way, by the way, 79% of their employees are technologists.
Roblox is more of a tech company than Google or any other tech company.
This is an incredible firm.
When's the last time you saw an IPO pulled because the market was so strong?
They thought maybe we're not thinking big enough.
We're seeing that the next DaVinci, the next Frescoes, the next real creative voices
are going to come from different platforms.
We're seeing the traditional gatekeepers, whether it's the Pope or the Medici's
or whether it's movie studios or creative executives being sort of shifted aside
and saying with your iPhone and this platform, we're going to let the end consumer decide
what is the creativity that they want to absorb.
By the way, I said DaVinci, that's actually Michelangelo.
And by the way, I would have heard that I would have gotten like 10 or 15 comments
in my Twitter feed and my LinkedIn profile from the guardians of gotcha.
Save your breath.
A gaming platform fit for the great dispersion.
250 million a year, almost three hours a day, more than double.
Kids are spending more than double the time on Roblox.
They're spending on TikTok.
And again, the majority of US children on this platform and incredible flywheel.
You get the point.
Where is this dispersion going?
We're going to see many of these platforms accelerate.
I'm going to see many of the traditional gatekeepers get their shit kicked out of them
because they like the existing film creative industrial complex, right?
Podcasts get featurized and there's a flurry of acquisitions.
Why?
If you have an industry where there's high NPS and low multiples and low revenues,
then it makes sense for a low NPS high revenue company to come in and say,
I know, I know if we launch transparent and the marvelous Mrs.
Maisel and people like us more and we just decrease churn from 80% to 70% or we
decrease, we increase renewal from 90% to 93%.
We can monetize it in some in some high NPS products are used to sell more paper
towels and more handsets.
And the ultimate arbitrage here is in podcasting.
People are very fond and have real goodwill towards their favorite podcast.
But but the industry is so small.
It hasn't really been monetized.
So you see these incredible arbitrage deals.
Hollywood's essentially been featurized.
It used to be a business that had to be profitable in and among itself.
But the big guys realized, you know what?
I can spend more money than I take in as long as I sign up more prime memberships
and sell more handsets.
This is effectively featurized all of entertainment where it's no longer a
business in and among itself, but simply a feature to differentiate a better
business specifically big tech.
They're all going vertical.
What happened when House of Cards was launched on Netflix and they went
vertical their stock skyrocketed.
It's happening again.
Look at what happened when Spotify was just not vertical not investing in
proprietary differentiated content not increasing their NPS and then they do
a hundred million dollar deal.
By the way, Joe Rogan got ripped off the stocks up 126 percent since they
announced this deal.
There's going to be a race to acquire this high NPS talent to differentiate
platforms who can monetize it to a much greater extent than these companies
can monetize themselves again.
It's the arbitrage of NPS take every independent podcast across all categories
and they're starting to get calls from the bigger platform saying hey, what
do you make you make 5 million?
Would you like 50 million?
Because all I need is one basis point 50 basis point increase in my NPS and I
can monetize it to a greater extent and you're still the cheapest way for me to
differentiate myself a hundred million dollars or Joe Rogan.
He got ripped off are going to see a dispersion of education.
We're going to see more unicorns and Edtech than almost any other sectors a
percentage of how many unicorns are now why because people as such as myself
and my boss have transferred 1.6 trillion dollars in wealth for middle
class households to universities.
Why so University administrators can have less accountability and make more
money if it sounds morally corrupt trust your instincts.
What's happening huge disruption specifically at the hands of our cash
chow cows that have decided they don't want to show up to a covid infested
racist country called the US and we're seeing an absolute destruction or an
absenteeism of international students who are our cash cows the number of
international students that show up for the first time is off 43% and it is
declined 16% in general.
Look at the number of international students are the decline in the number of
international students as a percentage of student body the top MBA programs.
This is just in 12 months in some in some they're just not coming to school.
We did an analysis of which universities would be hit hardest or do the best
post covid our methodology simple.
We looked at value their credential essentially the brand we looked at the
experience is based on a company called Niche of student life and we looked at
the NPV the present value of the bump you got from that education in that
credential.
We then did all of this or set all of this over tuition and we looked at
vulnerabilities specifically the shock absorber of the endowment for student
job a lot of money you can weather almost any storm and also their
vulnerability around those international students or their cash cows more
international students the more cash cows you're likely going to lose during
the pandemic and then and then we just articulated and parses into four
quadrants and what did I get the next day a lot of activity on this post
probably more activity on this post than I've ever received and for the first
time not one not two, but three cease and desist letters isn't it night isn't
it nice to be threatened to spend 35 years of your life without ever getting
any sort of legal action threatened much less pursued and then to have
chancellors and University administrators send you cease and desist
letters specifically they wanted us to say this data is not accurate and stop
trashing us because we're worried our students aren't going to show up and
pay full freight for our near Ivy like experience that we're overcharging for
when we when we foist the feces of a university like experience in other
words give them a Hyundai worth of education for Mercedes like price we're
going to see a massive inflow into the disruption of Ed Tech 750 billion
dollars is no longer to be getting dispersed through the traditional
channels of universities and as a result we're going to see an explosion
and remote and online learning and also hybrids that partner with universities
the dispersion in healthcare is probably the most exciting disruptive
transition and stakeholder value in history Walmart Walmart is going to
continue to get further deeper deeper into healthcare with acquisitions our
health care in this country is shameful we spend more than any country in the
world except we have worse outcomes so the way to describe health healthcare
would be the same way to describe San Francisco as a city expensive but bad
Walmart has the scale they actually actually have a fantastic means of
testing their healthcare and Walmart there's a Walmart closer to Americans
and most hospitals they're going to roll out a healthcare incrementally through
acquisitions and innovations similar to what they're doing with their health
clinics where they offer primary care and standard procedures at a very
reasonable cost Amazon will begin to perform the Jedi mind trick they
perform on most industries on healthcare and over the next 12 months they will
Literally grab a hundred billion dollars from existing healthcare companies just
by threatening to go into healthcare and just with press releases look what
happened look what happened to these guys every time Amazon announces good
numbers its stock goes up and other retailers go down why because people have
figured out what's good for Amazon is bad for the rest of retail well what is
about to be good for Amazon is about to be bad for the rest of healthcare.
This is a company that added one and a half trillion dollars at the expense of
other retailers.
What does it need to do though?
It has a lot of it has a problem the law big numbers it needs to add about a
half a quarter of a trillion dollars in top line revenue to maintain the
velocity of its stock.
It's going to go after healthcare healthcare companies the 10 biggest at
it 80 billion dollars in market capitalization.
What does that mean?
Where's that coming from when Amazon announces that it's doing something with
Berkshire Hathaway and JP Morgan everybody else begins to shed value to
Amazon and we're going to see the same thing over and over this year the
dispersion of markets right.
We're no longer going into brokerages.
We're no longer dealing with stockbrokers.
It's coming to our handheld phone.
Dispersion is not all good.
There are some very dangerous things because it disperses and it skips not
only channels of distribution.
It can skip regulation or sometimes needed needed friction.
I believe 2021 is the year we get a new menace that joins Robin Hood or excuse
me the joins lift and uber and Facebook.
The new menace is online trading app Robin Hood Robin Hood traders trade 88
times the number of options when size adjusted is any other platform.
We also have an organization that is not thinking of its investors as as the
customer but the product that produces data that they then sell to other hedge
funds who front run these trades or want insight and what the dumb money is
doing and they are able to garner much more revenue than any other firm based
on the trading data of their products specifically their consumers.
What could go wrong here options that is total share of revenues is very dangerous
exotic instruments that are not for first-time investors over index at Robin
Hood and we're also seeing the algebra of deterrence is not working here.
The SEC is now find them for a second time for not being transparent around
how they are monetizing their consumers data.
They find them 2 million and 10 million and guess what Robin Hood like Facebook
just don't give a shit right?
Why would you if you have a parking meter in front of your house that costs
a hundred bucks and the ticket is 25 cents.
Let's break the law and that's what Robin Hood is doing similar to what
Facebook did when they continue to wave the middle finger in the face of
regulators because doesn't matter we can write we can stroke a track for
five billion dollars.
That's about 11 days of cash flow.
Look at Charles Schwab when you want to invest you get messages saying the
following make sure you have your short-term needs covered a relatively
low-risk investment.
What happens when you go on to the Robin Hood app right?
Hi there instant access.
You're going to get instant deposits get your get your first free share of
stock now and then you do anything and boom boom what happens it starts to
rain confetti.
Let's create behavioral triggers that release dopamine and get you addicted
in a bull market.
What could go wrong?
We are considering additional criteria and education for customers seeking
level 3 options authorization to help ensure customers understand more
sophisticated options trading.
What are they talking about?
They're talking about their response to a 20 year old Alex Kearns who
received an errant incorrect statement from Robin Hood saying that he was
down $700,000 no the firm $700,000 and seeing no way out decided that his
way out was to throw himself in front of a train and this is their response
and to be fair what have they done fucking nothing.
I don't know these two founders.
All I know is they don't have sons if we could go back in time and stop one
menace from depressing our teens and weaponizing our elections.
Would we do anything about it?
That's where we are now.
These two are menaces.
There is good news.
The good news the Massachusetts Secretary of Commonwealth Galvin says Robin
Hood is a reckless company gamifying investing more of this to come.
Goldman Sachs CEO puts out a very thoughtful note that the markets
who ever valued it's bad all this volatility yet they've decided they're
going to be the lead underwriter for Robin Hood boss.
Walk the walk make the music match the words.
This company has no business in the market supposedly when Robin Hood had
an outage last week volatility skyrocketed and volume went way down.
What could go wrong?
This firm is not only bad for young men.
It is bad for the markets and inject systemic risk into the markets.
Next prediction spacks underperform.
We've seen record levels of spacks, right?
I mean unbelievable number of spacks record year and we're seeing about
we've seen about 70 billion dollars.
It is still unspacked meaning it's been raised but they haven't found a target
special-purpose acquisition Corp.
You go raise money and then you say I'm going to go find a target.
I've done all the hard work of getting a company public boom just add water
public company they get to be they get to trade right away.
And so we're going to go out and find a great private company.
So 70 billion dollars.
It's usually it's usually leveraged two or three to one with additional debt
once they find a target once they find a target, but we've seen incredible
incredible interest in this because never underestimate the markets ability
to produce a product when people have cash in their hand.
Just think of it as when you're in New York and it starts to rain before
you know it.
There's umbrellas for sale everywhere.
Well, there are a ton of umbrellas for sale right now in the form of spacks.
What does this mean?
There's 200 billion dollars searching for private companies right now.
That means that these spacks by General Motors Ford, Boeing Fiat Chrysler
Delta United JetBlue and American Airlines.
They would still have money.
The question is are there that many great private companies that are sort
of IPO ready and most likely the answer is no Bitcoin or passes $50,000 as
we've been writing this or preparing we've been working on this presentation
for a month.
I think Bitcoin is up five to $7,000.
I think of Bitcoin.
I don't fully understand it.
I had Michael Saylor on the prop G pod yesterday to try and explain it to me
and I got to be honest.
I still don't fully understand Bitcoin.
But the way I think about it is I think about it as a company and a brand and
right now even with its run up to I think 23,000 today.
It has a market capitalization of $400 billion.
So if you took all the coins time to value, it's 400 billion.
It's about the worth of Johnson & Johnson.
I think of this thing though is somewhat true or not.
Its perception is it's a hedge against inflation.
It represents Liberty and it represents the new gold and the thing about this is
you can create a go bag and you can stick $10 million of gold in your head with
an access code where you can't do that with gold or you can do with Bitcoin.
You can't do with gold.
I believe this asset class is going to breach a trillion dollars, which means
it goes to $50,000 if that sounds like very unsophisticated analysis,
trust your instincts, but that doesn't mean I'm wrong.
Doesn't mean I'm wrong.
This thing is now Bitcoin is now getting the institutional support to give people
the security mainline investors to start putting a percentage of their assets in to Bitcoin.
And then if you look at the government's ability, all government's ability to just print
tremendous amounts of money, you could make an argument that in fact cash is going to
incur a decrease in purchasing power and that this might be seen as a more sophisticated,
more millennial, more hip version of gold as a hedge to inflation that may in fact
become a tangible threat soon.
This is evidenced by the fact that the increase in Bitcoin seems to be inversely correlated
to people pulling out funds or correlated to people pulling funds out of gold ETFs.
In other words, people perceive Bitcoin as being gold like and are transferring their
assets in gold into Bitcoin.
And by the way, there's a lot more than $400 billion invested in gold right now.
Let's talk about the dispersion of media.
Disney stock will rise 30% on move to a Rondo.
The gangster move here, what happens when you move to recurring revenue?
Well, the red bar is the increase in revenue and the blue bar is the increase in stock price.
So how do these companies arbitrage this increase in revenue with an outsized increase in
stakeholder value?
Simple, they move to a recurring revenue bundle and Disney is prime.
They have the assets and they are about to go full Rondo.
Now we made this prediction again about a month ago and the stock is up 20 or 30% since
then, but it still has a lot of legs.
Go on LinkedIn, go on LinkedIn, do some basic searches and you can find out they are lining
up the Rondo tanks at the border.
Look at all the job.
Look at the descriptions of all the jobs.
They are looking to fill right now.
They've also done a major reord to go full Rondo and rally around Disney Plus.
Why?
Because they've decided what is strategy?
All strategy boils down to one thing.
What can we do?
It is really hard that other people can't do.
Well, what other people can't do is launch a series on young Lando or take Jedi Ashoka
and put her on TV or monetize the hundred billion dollars in acquisitions of Pixar,
Lucasfilm and Marvel.
This company has so much momentum right now.
Oh, and by the way, let's give people a baby Yoda doll and give them the opportunity to
take their sons to Disney and have a special Edge of Galaxy experience.
So they make their own lightsabers.
Oh, and by the way, if you want to come to our parks when it's not crowded, you need
to be a Disney Plus member and maybe even we get you a better cabin on Disney Cruises.
This is the ultimate Rondo.
Anyone with kids has to join this thing called Disney Plus.
They'll have pricing power and the marketplace will look at their revenues and it'll recast
the multiple on this company similar to what's happened to Apple over the last five years.
We wrote about this by the way, just as snap has been the product planning and development
for Facebook.
Who has been the strategy department for AT&T and Disney?
That's right us.
Anyway, we're going full Rondo late TNT stock.
It's $40 a share and or divest HP or CNN.
They had an acquisition.
They've lost control of the narrative stocks are now more narrative than they are numbers
and they've lost control the narrative the narrative right now is basically the following.
It's basically you made a bad acquisition when they are going to get control of the narrative.
They're going to take it back.
They did the baller move here despite all the complaints of people making tens of millions
of dollars with the existing channels of film and does what a shocker that the head of CAA
and Christopher Nolan making between 10 and 50 million dollars a year off the existing
infrastructure think it's a really bad idea.
They should have a petty party hosted by Jeffrey Katzenberg with Billy Squire and Alan Thicke
or Robin Thicke play and it could be catered by Planet Hollywood thought that'd be funnier.
That didn't quite work out.
We are going to see the multiple on AT&T go up for every one basis point and multiple
that AT&T gets back by recasting and reclaiming the narrative.
They increase their market capitalization by 1.7 billion dollars and this is how they're
going to do it.
This was the baller move of media when they decided to take everything directly to HBO
Max and by the way who decided to agree to their terms all of a sudden Roku why because
HBO Max has just gotten a giant EpiPen tea therapy whatever the hell you want to call
it.
They all of a sudden have unbelievable new mojo and they are either going to show every
invigorated story that'll take AT&T stock up or they will spin HBO and possibly CNN
who is going to go behind to pay while why because advertising is a tax on the poor and
the technologically literate and no good content should be ad supported.
We spend two weeks a year watching commercials read Zakaria one of my professional role models
amazing show 14 minutes of commercial time and what do they get for that for pelting
you with reminders how much it sucks to get old and say we can solve your opioid induced
constipation or make your legs less restless.
They get 23 cents for shoveling that shit down your throat right or for 14 minutes of
ads they get 23 cents from an advertiser and this is a great show that advertisers love.
Another way of thinking about this is the advertising industrial complex and Time Warner
believes that your time is worth approximately a dollar an hour.
No it's not.
No it's not your time is worth more at least a buck ten maybe more maybe more.
So what are they going to do?
They're going to recognize the way you create trillions of dollars or at least billions
of dollars in shareholder values from a time machine.
Netflix isn't a media company it's a time machine if you only let your kids watch Netflix
they save two weeks of their life a year with advertising the markets realize this and
realize non ad supported recurring revenue companies are a better business and have taken
their stocks up substantially over the last 12 months.
It's a better business model.
What's the most bulletproof media company in the world right now?
The New York Times.
It's not old versus new it's subscription versus ad base and the New York Times which
gets two thirds of its revenue from subscription is now monetizing them through the tomb of
sixty six bucks apiece.
We're going to see the best content on the progressive side go behind a paywall.
Let's summarize.
This is the beginning of the end of big tech as we know it.
We're going to see antitrust.
However, however, Facebook stock will increase in the face of antitrust is the only person
who loses here is the Zuck and Amazon is going to prophylactically spin a WS.
The dispersion of HQ is going to result in a co-working Renaissance restoration hardware
becomes a breaches a thousand Sony Sonos forty dollars a share.
The Apple B becomes worth more than Uber.
Apple acquires Peloton.
We're seeing a dispersion of retail big acquisitions for Shopify and or Zoom which could be seen
as the AOL of 2021.
This thing is very vulnerable sitting on top of a hundred and twenty billion dollar market
cap.
We're seeing a dispersion of education.
We're going to see more unicorns and education as a percentage of existing unicorns of any
other sector.
We're seeing a dispersion of creativity.
Roblox triples in value.
Podcasts get feature eyes and we see a flurry of acquisitions of the strongest ones that
are still independent.
A dispersion of markets.
People are recognizing that dispersion is not necessarily a good thing if we don't have
friction of regulation.
Robinhood is being recognized for what it is.
A menace.
Spacks will underperform.
There's too many hunting too few good companies.
Bitcoin hits fifty thousand dollars.
We see a dispersion of health care.
Walmart gets into health care via acquisition.
Amazon starts to perform their Jedi mind trick and drain the ten biggest health care companies
of their market capitalization.
And we're seeing a dispersion of media.
Disney stock will continue to accelerate based on their ballerrundle.
It was a sleeping giant that was prodded and poked and is finally waking up.
AT&T stock hits forty dollars a share and or a divest HBO and CNN goes behind a paywall.
Let's open it up to questions.
Go ahead.
Knowing that particularly in the US in 2020 we've seen both the stock market and unemployment
rise significantly.
Do you foresee there being meaningful steps taken by the government to address income
inequality in 2021 or do you imagine that we simply see the K-shaped recovery continue?
What's your name?
Katie.
Katie, where are you from, Katie?
Astoria, New York.
Katie from Astoria.
I hope so.
In New York, Katie, when you walk in the street, you are just as likely as we sit here and
now to find to run into somebody who has been to a food bank as has a college degree.
Thirty four percent of New Yorkers have been to a food bank in the last 30 days and 32
percent have a college degree.
So we now have a great state with the capital of the world as more people have been to a
food bank than have a college degree.
The stimulus of the pandemic was nothing but a corrupt government playing the economy
like a Stradivarius violin and figuring out a way to flatten the curve for rich people.
Small businesses didn't need a bailout.
It's ridiculous that we've decided to keep restaurants open while maintaining schools,
letting schools stay closed.
We have decided to be very loving and empathetic towards companies and to be harsh and Darwinistic
towards individuals.
The basis of capitalism, the only way capitalism works is when you flip that and that is you
let companies go out of business.
You let people get fired.
You have Darwinism.
You have full body contact violence at a corporate level, which creates incredible prosperity
such that we can be more loving and empathetic to Americans.
We can take 38 percent of seniors who are in poverty and take it down to 11 percent
social security.
We can take people who are hungry and say, sorry, you live in the wealthiest country
in the world.
We're not going to let you be hungry.
That is snap.
We have lost the script.
I am hopeful that through a series of DOJ actions that economically go through and oxygenate
the economy by breaking up big tech, I am hopeful that we have individuals and leadership
now that feel some sense of empathy.
I'm hopeful that our citizenship has woken up to the fact that if we live in a nation
that is not a nation, if we don't have some empathy, if we don't grab the hands of our
sisters and brothers and recognize that we need to have progressive taxes, we need to
redistribute income, that we can have the wealthiest nation in the world with people
starving, that we have lost the script.
Capitalism is absolutely collapsing on itself.
I am hopeful we are at a juncture, but it is up to us.
The world isn't what it is.
The world is what we make of it.
So I am very hopeful around the Biden-Harris administration, but we are going to have to
give them cloud cover and decide that it is unacceptable for anyone in this country to
be hungry.
It is unacceptable for companies to dominate.
It is unacceptable for a tyranny of private power to overwhelm our government.
We need regulation.
We need fair taxes.
It is ridiculous that one man has more wealth than every individual in D.C., Vermont, Wyoming,
Nevada, and Alaska, and adds the wealth of the Dakotas in a good week and doesn't pay
any taxes.
We have lost the script.
Capitalism is about violence of corporations and empathy and love with people.
We need to protect people, not companies.
I am hopeful.
Next question.
Hey, Scott.
I am hopeful, too.
Nice meeting you.
My question is, toilet paper, PPE, and software that aids remote learning and working were
like the hottest commodities of 2020.
What is your prediction for the lineup of 2021 of those items?
Well, I, okay, so let's talk about toilet paper and the pandemic.
We are about to have the worst four months in American history in terms of loss of souls.
We are going to lose more people in the next four or five months, and we lost in World
War II because we have this cold comfort that a technology solution is here called a vaccine,
and people are going to loosen their behavior, and we are going to have record levels of
deaths.
So I don't know if that's, you know, if you are saying terrible things around the pandemic
are related to the sales of toilet paper, they will continue to escalate.
I do think online learning is here to stay.
I had 280 kids in my class at Stern each paying $7,000.
It's $1.96 million or $166,000 a night for me to do this.
That is not sustainable, and I think a lot of people are going to decide to cherry pick
individual classes or get certification at a lower.
Calculus is a $2 billion business in America.
Undergraduates pay $2 billion to take calculus classes.
Outly or another company I have no investment in says, well, let's get the best calculus
teacher that's been taught the same way for 100 years and give it to people, kids, for
$300 instead of $7,000.
So I think toilet paper, I think the pandemic, unfortunately, gets worse in terms of the
toll it takes on Americans, but I'm hopeful about remote learning.
I appreciate the question.
Next question!
Hi, Scott.
I was inspired by your new episode on Bitcoin with Michael Saylor today, and he explained
it very, very clearly as to what it is and the trajectory.
My question is, as a personal investor, what percentage would you dedicate to that Bitcoin
compared to the overall investment portfolio, especially since we all agree that stocks
are so frothy and overvalued?
It's just stupid.
So anyway, Bitcoin, percentage, investment portfolio allocation.
What's your name?
Where are you from?
Your name and where are you from?
Clara in Brooklyn.
Clara in Brooklyn, New Yorkers today.
Clara, so first off, read my colleague's Aswath de Moteran's blog.
He's going to forget more than I'm going to know about diversification and allocation.
I'll just give you a viewpoint.
You look like you're in your 20s.
You're young.
You have a lot of time to make money.
You always guess to the low side, Clara.
You always guess to the low side.
Anyways, anyways, you still have a decent amount of time to make money.
So if you feel convicted about something, putting 10 or 20 percent of your net worth
in something you really feel strongly about, I think is OK.
I think as you get to be my age, you never want to have more than 10 percent of your
worth in any one stock or asset class.
So I would say if you're in love with Bitcoin, you know, at a minimum, maybe get your feet
wet, see what the price says.
When you get your feet wet, you start following it.
You start understanding it.
You start getting comfortable with it.
And then if it goes down, maybe buy a little bit more.
You don't have to go all in at once.
And then Bitcoin strikes me as the kind of thing where you want to buy it and forget
about it.
I think it's going to be volatile.
But I believe I'm like you.
I'm actually thinking of putting some money into Bitcoin.
I don't own any.
And I'm going to put somewhere between five and 10 percent of my net worth in it and just
think of it as the kind of thing I'll give to my kids.
And if shit gets real and there's some sort of like crazy market disruption, I'm going
to hope that it is what everyone else says and it's a hedge against the rest of the world.
But I also like to remind people that when the market dove in April, Bitcoin hit five
thousand dollars.
So I'm not sure there is truly any uncorrelated asset class circling back to your question.
Dip your toes in.
Try not to go above 10 percent.
Learn about it.
So I would say five to 10 percent.
More importantly, go to somebody who knows what they're talking about and read ASOT,
the Motorins blog.
Thank you for the question.
Last question.
Thanks, Scott.
There's two of them.
There's two of you.
There's two of us.
Who are you?
Hey, I'm Jack.
I'm Alex.
Where are you calling from?
We're in New York.
Are you guys married?
Are you living in sin?
Living in sin.
Oh, my gosh.
This is the R-rated part of the live stream.
Nice.
All right.
What's your question?
So with so many companies on the coast looking at relocating, like Wall Street to Florida
and Silicon Valley to Texas, what do you think happens to traditional mega cities and their
subsequent commuter towns?
I think the death of cities has been greatly exaggerated.
San Francisco is just incredibly poorly run.
And I lived in San Francisco for 10 years.
Most beautiful city in the nation.
It's expensive at bat, overpriced.
That's just a micro climate.
But cities are still the place that the most talented people in the world want to go to
bump off, to get creativity, the serendipity of ideas, the grit, the culture, the great
food, the great art.
Cities are still going to be where two thirds of economic creativity, economic growth happens
over the next 20 to 30 years.
Advice to a young person, get certified, get to a city.
Because once you start collecting dogs and kids, it's hard to stay in a city.
So the time to get to a city is when you're young.
You guys are probably, I'm going to assume you're double income, no children.
The city is where you want to be.
And granted, there'll be some people who already have careers, already have some money, already
have kids, already have dogs who take advantage of the remote work from home and will move
to the suburbs or move to more remote places and increase their quality of life.
But the real friction, the real fire, the real fur that flies around stakeholder creation
as it relates to corporations and creativity is going to be in these amazing things called cities.
It might be Miami instead of San Francisco.
It might be St. Louis instead of Chicago.
But my advice to anyone under the age of 40 is get to a city, get to a city.
Thank you so much.
This has been great.
We are going to wrap up with a quick notion on prosperity versus progress.
This is very preachy, so I want to apologize in advance.
This could be the best or the worst year in decades, or specifically my prediction is
that 2021 is either the Renaissance of America or the point that everybody looks at in the
history books as the decline of our civilization.
This is either going to be the best year or the worst year in decades.
Specifically, there's incredible opportunity.
We could take education costs down.
We could take admittance rates of UCLA back to where it was when I got in, 60% versus
where it is now, 12%.
We could get off our heels in terms of health care and provide primary care to people in
need at a fraction of the cost using remote.
This could be more time for fathers with their family.
This could be more opportunity for people to bond, for mates and spouses to reconnect,
for us to spend the kind of time we want to spend with our parents as they get infirmed
and aged.
There's an enormous opportunity for profitability as firms no longer have to spend 15% of their
revenue on commercial real estate, but just five.
We could permanently lower emissions through a reduction in commuting.
We could spend less time in bad hotels eating bad salty food on shitty planes and hurting
our backs and aging quickly.
If there's anything that's taken 10 years off my life, it's business travel, which I
used to do 200 days a year.
Commuting is a tax on our souls.
It could end.
Business travel could end.
There's huge opportunities.
At the same time, there's some very, very unhealthy trends here.
We have gone from a dysfunctional economy to a dystopic one.
The 0.1% is killing it.
We don't like to say this, the top 10%, which I'm in, the pandemic has meant if you're blessed
enough to not have an impact on your health, it's meant more time with kids, Netflix, and
your stocks are up.
However, it's taken an enormous toll.
One in six households food insecure with children.
This is the scariest chart I've seen all year.
Typically, low-income kids track with middle and higher-income kids in public schools around
math and science.
But since COVID-19 and the introduction of remote learning, low-income kids have fallen
off the map.
Why?
Maybe they don't have iPads.
Maybe their iPads get stolen.
Maybe they're not broadband.
Maybe mom can't stay home and sit next to them.
By the way, remote learning just basically means mom is now the teacher.
Let's be honest, it's almost always the mom.
But we've seen them fall off the map.
Despite of the moral problems here, we're going to lose half our scientists.
We're going to lose half our military leaders.
We're going to lose half our civic leaders.
We are literally losing a generation.
We're also seeing incredible increases in unemployment among low-income people.
If you make over $100,000 a year, there's been no change in unemployment.
If you make less than $40,000 a year, there's a 40% likelihood you've had some interruption
in your employment.
We're also seeing small businesses get their shit kicked out of them.
But wait, the NASDAQ's up.
If our spending and our priorities are reflected in our national character, then we have said
that losing half a million Americans would be bad.
But what would be profoundly tragic is if the NASDAQ went down.
This stimulus had nothing to do with saving people.
This stimulus was about flattening the curve for rich people and seeing the markets go
apeshit.
We have lost the script.
Should the markets be higher?
Should rich people be wealthier?
Coming out of the pandemic, just as food insecurity hits all-time highs and a third of Americans
are worried about paying their rent, this isn't capitalism.
When you have capitalism on the way up and then you have bailouts for rich people and
corporations on the way down, that's cronyism.
No wonder young people don't buy into capitalism.
We need to return to capitalism.
We need more empathy.
The hard part about dispersion as a cousin to dispersion is segregation.
We no longer see the homeless veteran on the off ramp because we're not commuting to work.
We no longer see people from different income levels or the single mother bringing us our
food because we're not in restaurants and we're not in malls.
We no longer see different people of different ethnicities because if we have any money,
we send them to all white private schools or we don't in fact interact with people in
different neighborhoods.
The problem is when there's no segregation, our empathy decreases for other communities.
We need to re-embrace truth.
There has to be a truth again in our society and the closest thing we have to truth is
science and let's do the science, let's do the data around this vaccine.
All this bullshit narrative around the risks, you are much more likely to be killed by your
own dog than have an adverse reaction to results in death from a vaccine.
Vaccines are the best thing to ever happen to us and you know what really frightens me
when I'm hearing from my friends and my cohort?
The following, I'm going to wait.
I'm going to wait.
This is the narcissist playbook.
I'm going to see what the long term effects are.
I'm going to take the vaccine but I'm going to wait.
Well guess what?
This isn't about you.
Why?
If we don't get to herd immunity, we're going to have another 200 million infections at
a 1% mortality rate.
That means 2 million Americans are going to die and maybe they're browner than you, maybe
they're heavier than you, maybe they're older than you and you've decided that you really
don't have that bigger risk from COVID-19.
Well guess what?
This isn't fucking about you.
This is about not being a threat in the web of death that is combing our nation and snaring
vulnerable people because of the asymptomatic carriers who have no effects from this.
I'm going to wait.
In 1940, in May of 1940, there were 400,000 Belgian, French, Dutch and British troops
who were driven to the shores of Dunkirk and had no way out.
They were trapped.
It was going to be a turkey shoot.
And the call went out to Britain that they needed to get these 400,000 men off the beach
and anyone with a sailboat, a fishing boat, anything that floated didn't think, well,
I'm going to weigh the risks.
They didn't know if there was Messerschmitts out there.
They didn't know if there were U-boats.
They didn't know if they were going to drown in bad weather.
They heard the call and they answered it and they saved 400,000 people.
There are 2 million of our American brothers and sisters on a beach right now that are
going to die unless we answer the call.
And the call is to get a vaccine.
Hear the call.
Have any of us had to answer a call to be patriots?
There are so few of us, including myself, who have done almost nothing in exchange for
the liberties and the prosperity we've enjoyed.
Be that person.
Answer the call.
This isn't about you.
This is about our brothers and sisters who are vulnerable.
Let's get them off the beach.
My name is Scott Galloway.
I teach at NYU and I appreciate your time.
Our goal is to make you more successful professionally and personally.
If you can attract the right people, things will be better.
It's usually work out.
Companies with recurring revenue relationships tend to outperform and build stakeholder value
faster.
Gross margin is the accountant's proof or source of truth around differentiation.
Best in class firms are constantly evaluating their competitors to identify substitutes
at all four levels.
Innovation should always be about papering over the gap between what you're able to
provide or what the market's able to provide and what customers actually want.
As you introduce more and more product features, you should be consistently evaluating the
user experience for friction and pain points.
There are many ways to leverage brand to increase perceived value and stakeholder value.
The basic rule here on crisis management is pretty simple.
Do the right thing.
A set of shortcuts that signal excellence and quality to the end consumer.
Anyways, when they do drink beer, I just spit on myself, we're going to keep right going.