Apple's headset is going to be one of the biggest tech failures.
I think it's going to rival the Oculus, and it will officially be the most elegant final
nail in the coffin of this sort of headset-driven VR consensual hallucination.
I think that Apple likely greenlit this project a couple years ago when it looked like VR
offered more potential.
Everybody thinks that Mark Zuckerberg and Evan Spiegel are smarter than them, and everyone
wants to look and feel younger and wants to know what the youngins are thinking.
And I bet that Tim Cook said, we hate Mark Zuckerberg.
VR offers a lot of potential to go to Greece without going to Greece and perform heart
surgery from the Cleveland Clinic on a little girl in a developing country, whatever it
might be.
And I just don't think it's panning out.
And I think if they had it to do over, they would take that billion dollars back they've
spent on this thing and not release it.