You have predicted that Biden
will be re-elected and Trump
will go to jail in 2024.
How short can you be?
Why are you saying that?
Well, I don't think you can be
sure.
If you look at the
jurisdictions he's been charged
in, they have between a 70%
and 92% conviction rate,
and only a third of people who
receive the indictments
or the charges that he's
received don't end up
with prison time.
So even if you were to discount
those statistics or cut them
in half, because it is
a different situation,
it just seems mathematically
improbable that he won't be
sentenced to prison at some
point.
So it's become a bit of a game
show, and that is his objective
is to slow down the trials
until after.
But if you look at
statistically the likelihood
that one of these 93 charges
will stick, it just feels
mathematically likely something
is going to stick here.
So they say 91, but nonetheless,
we're just nitpicking here.
Thank you.
And you think these trials,
at least one of them,
will come to fruition
and sentencing before the election?
I think we'll find out
in the next couple of months.