Give me your prediction for the debate.
I'm not watching it, which is because, just to be blunt,
I think chances are he's going to do better than people think.
Her medium is being on an elevated podium
with questions prepped by staff.
And basically, she's playing what she was, district attorney
slash attorney general.
I don't think she's as good on her feet as he is.
I'm hoping that he continues to show signs of being
addled and cognitive decline.
I gotta be honest, Kara, I'm really worried about it.
I think the expectations around her momentum have become too high.
I think he's good on his feet.
So I just can't watch it.
I'm too nervous about it.
The other thing is he could appear too quiet, like too...
They want happy Trump, but there's also comatose Trump.
You've seen it before, right?
He did it at the economic club, that kind of Trump.
And that shows lack of energy, so he seems old.
That is his problem.
She's just got to be as sharp as a fucking tack.
She really does.
The one piece of advice I would have for the Harris campaign would be
stop falling into the same trap Democrats have been falling into
for the last two years.
And that is we spend all of our capital and energy talking about
why he would be bad for America.
She needs to totally focus on why she would be good for America.
She needs to show a series of policies she needs to come across as,
in my view, a little bit wonky.
It has to be, I got my hands on the wheel.