What's super interesting here, and it kind of chills down my spine thinking about it,
is that essentially it's going to become more human-like.
When you think about why you go to the media, you go for news, right?
But almost everyone has access to the same news, unless you're spreading misinformation
or disinformation, which is kind of their new go-to so they can pretend it's news and
act like they've discovered something new and they haven't, they just made up something.
Oh, Dominion voting machines are linked to Hugo Chavez.
No, that's not news, that's a lie.
But real news is very hard to find, and it's very difficult to differentiate a media product
on news, right?
We don't differentiate on news.
We take other people's news and try and provide some insight or perspective, which is really
just Latin for voice.
Most people go to a media outlet for voice, and that is a take on things or insight or
humor or no voice.
I really like Reuters because I find Reuters is kind of just the facts, ma'am, right?
I also like The Economist because I find it very dry and looks at stuff through sort of
a capitalist lens.
Anyways, what it got me thinking about is the voice, if you will have chat GPT for Omni
or O, every morning I could just say, hey, give me today's business news in the voice
of Reuters, and I'll be able to say it just similar to what I used to do with Alexa.
And what this does is it's going to fulfill the dream of these big tech firms that are
increasingly consolidated, and that is what Google hated was that you left Google.
You type in lowest airfare from New York to St. Barts, right?
And it would bring up a bunch of paid for sites, including United, including JetBlue,
and then you would leave and go to JetBlue.
And then I said, no, no, no, we don't want anyone leaving.
So they started sending you to other components of Google, and Google has Google Flight or
Google Travel so they could further monetize it.
I think this could be really bad news for media organizations because at some point
it just might be easier for me to go, give me a view on campus protests in the voice
of Anderson Cooper, and I won't need to go to the CNN site.
It'll just keep me right there.