I think Vice President Harris is going to win the election.
I think there's a few things that will
carry her across the finish line.
When I look at the attributes of,
I don't know if they'll be sexist girls,
they're more organized.
They are.
They are a little bit more meticulous.
And I think when it comes to election day,
I think a lot of young women are going
to find a way to schedule time and get to the booth.
Young men, just bottom line, as someone
who's raising young men, I affectionately call them dopes.
Their prefrontal cortex does not catch up until the age of 25.
Yeah, they're not voting, right?
Because they're too young.
That would be illegal.
Well, yeah, at 117, I asked him, who would you vote for?
And he goes, well, I'd vote for Harris
because you're voting for her.
And I'm like, I hate and love that answer.
Anyways, but my point is, I think women are motivated.
Quite frankly, they're more organized.
Young women are going to do better at showing up
on election day.
I'd like to think that young men are getting the message
around a need to protect.
Or I'd like to think that that's a theme
that's resonating here, that they do see that there
is a certain level of demonization and attack
for special interest groups.
And I'd like to think they're stepping up.
And three, and again, this might be confirmation bias.
I'm just too emotional here.
But I think this self-inflicted, unforced error
around Puerto Rico with 400,000 to 500,000 Puerto Ricans
in Pennsylvania could be very, very, could.