And finally, just practically speaking,
you're not gonna lose your TikTok.
A ban is terrible use of words.
They're saying if you don't sell this thing,
we're gonna ban it.
They will sell it,
because there's too much money involved.
The reason TikTok in the secondary market
is trading at a $250 billion value on secondary markets,
for secondary shares,
is because of this overhang around US political tensions.
Their biggest investors are in China and in the US,
and they're capitalists.
General Atlantic partners, Sequoia,
some very big hedge funds and investors in China.
They're not gonna let that $250 billion be wiped out.
When the threat is credible,
this bill passes,
within a few weeks,
ByteDance announces they are selling to Western interests,
they get to keep their money,
and you still get your TikTok.
This isn't a ban.
This is saying we need the ownership structure
to change for defense reasons.
I think it's gonna happen.