Thanks for having me. My name is Scott Galloway. I teach at NYU and I appreciate your time today.
I'm coming to you live from a small a small sandbar in the Atlantic called Nantucket. Over the course
of the next 35 minutes I'll be taking you through approximately 130 slides and then hopefully we'll
leave time for 10 minutes of Q&A. So with that let's bust right into it. So we're going to talk
about COVID's enduring feature as more of an accelerant than a change agent. We'll also look
at some of these changes through the lens of the companies I spend the most time thinking about
Amazon, Apple, Facebook, and Google. We'll talk about an emerging crisis among young men and some
predictions for 2021 and then what we believe is the profound opportunity. Some disclosures, I have
investment stakes or ownerships in the following private and public companies. So just in terms of
if I sound as if I am promoting a company I probably am but these are the firms that I have
economic stakes in. Okay decades and days. There's a great quote attributed to Lenin that says
there are decades where nothing happens and there are weeks where decades happen. I think we're in
the former and that is we tend to think of time as a function of these astrophysical objects
circling a hot plasma called the sun but as humans we register time as a function of change and it
seems as if time is accelerating if you will. In the U.S. to give you a scale of the crisis here
just in one month last April we lost more Americans than we lost in the entire Vietnam conflict
and the numbers get even more staggering. At one point we were losing the same number of American
souls we lost in the attacks of 9-11 every 17 hours in the U.S. Obviously in Brazil and in India
we have seen the same type of mortality rates and is arguably the greatest public health crisis in
the last century. There's no easy way to segue to business. I'll just segue to business.
There have been three big shifts in our economy our modern economy. The first is globalization
comparative advantage. The second digitization simply put the internet and then I think we're
on the precipice of a third big shift in our modern economy and that is dispersion. What do
we mean by dispersion? So the ability to distribute products or services from the source creator to
the end user the end stakeholder reshaping the supply chain such that the source creator gets
greater margins and the end user gets to access the product with less friction or lower cost.
I think of it almost as leapfrogging right whether it's Peloton leapfrogging the gym
whether it's Wonder Woman 1984 coming directly to your TV in your home as opposed to having to go
to a theater whether it's Zoom bringing us to bringing work letting you rent your human capital
to an organization leapfrogging an office building or whether it's what we're doing now where we can
leapfrog the physical infrastructure of a conference and go directly to the end consumer. We're seeing
this dispersion of value if you will in a reshaping of the supply chain across almost every industry
and I think that presents tremendous opportunities and tremendous challenges and what will probably
be the greatest reshuffling of stakeholder value since the introduction of the internet.
The biggest industry that will be most impacted by this is healthcare and that is the healthcare
industrial complex is being dispersed. What do I mean by that? Probably 99 plus of the people who
have contracted endured and developed antibodies for the novel coronavirus will have never entered
a hospital much less a doctor's office. The number of people who were seeing doctors virtually has
absolutely exploded. It was less than one percent pre-pandemic it's almost a third now of visits are
done virtually. That will go down once the pandemic has subsided but it's not going back to one percent.
We've seen a similar phenomenon in Brazil where we've seen an explosion in telehealth. We're also
going to see a dispersion in education and that is in my industry we've used admissions departments
and the physical limits of a campus to gate or constrain artificially in my view the supply
of seats at great universities. I think a lot of the intellectual property and certification is
being dispersed to remote appliances such that we can expand hopefully expand the offering and
education can be dispersed. In the U.S. it's a 750 billion dollar business globally it's a two
trillion dollar business. Why is there such a rush to disperse education? Because my industry has
raised prices faster than almost any other industry maybe with the exception of healthcare. Tuition in
the U.S. is up 1400 percent in the last 30 years. To give you a sense of just how outrageous the
pricing has become I teach a course called brand strategy at the NYU Stern School of Business.
Every student has to spend seven thousand dollars U.S. to take my course not for the year that's
just to take my one course. I have 280 students in my class in the fall or put another way my
course generates approximately 1.96 million dollars just that one course. Now think about this I have
returned my compensation to the school for the last 10 years so I can continue to bite the hand
that doesn't feed me but try and imagine another product that gets a two million dollar price tag
with 98 points maybe 99 points of gross margin. The only other product I could find is a product
called Zolgensma which is a life-saving gene therapy that is literally a knockout drug. Two
doses of this cures a rare genetic disease so either cure save your life or brand strategy
with Professor Scott Galloway. I don't think either of those is sustainable. We're going to see
incredible dispersion of media. We use the example of media going straight to our smartphones or our
speakers and skipping not only the supply chain of movie theaters but skipping the traditional
arbiters of what gets greenlit. You can go on YouTube now you can go on TikTok and you can garner
a huge following without the permission or the green light from a studio executive or an agent.
Theaters are obviously being massively disrupted here in the U.S. When we think about media there's
really only two media formats that are growing over the top streaming and video games. Every other
media is suffering and losing oxygen if you will. We're also seeing an incredible dispersion in
finance and that is where disruption is typically a disruptor if you will or a new player comes in
and starts focusing on a market that's been overlooked because the incumbents see them as
unprofitable. An example of this in Argentina would be Walla that is going after the 50 percent
of Argentinians that don't have a bank account. Neobank in Brazil we are seeing incredible
disruption where people are going after these companies have access to cheap capital,
leveraging smartphones, leveraging technology and building from the ground up a cohort that
had previously been ignored. The result is the marketplace loves these disruptors and provides
them with valuations greater than the incumbents. So look at this PayPal is worth dramatically more
than Goldman Sachs and Square will soon be worth more than Morgan Stanley. These are financial
institutions that took generations some even centuries to build and these disruptors are
already have already garnered more stakeholder value. Crypto is a dispersion of trust from
central banks to new assets and also a younger generation that doesn't believe the current asset
classes are serving them well. When we have bailouts that prop up the markets there's a
general feeling among people under the age of 30 that they have to create their own asset classes
to have the same opportunities that their parents had and you're seeing tremendous traction
of these asset classes and adoption across institutions and retail. In the U.S. there are
now just as many people of color in the investment markets as whites mostly because they have engaged
with new trading apps and also they're interested in cryptocurrencies. So we talk about this in the
context of opportunity but there's also some very serious societal concerns specifically dispersion
if you will is kind of the evil cousin of segregation and that is when we no longer go to the mall the
movie theater or even to work we interact less often with people from different races and different
income classes and we lose empathy when we no longer see the homeless veteran the homeless person
the single mother at the mall the grocery store the movie theater we have less empathy for them.
There's been studies showing that when a minority group grows in population if you live near them
you have empathy for them if you do not live near them and they are segregated you begin to resent
them. Let's talk a little bit about the four. We are seeing these companies now have the power
and I believe the influence of nation states. I believe Amazon, Apple, Facebook, and Google are
singularly more powerful and influential than almost any entities in the world maybe the
exception of China in the U.S. and if you look at their market capitalizations and I realize it's
apples to oranges they have a greater economic value or market capitalization than the GDP of
several large nations. They are also becoming so dominant that they are beginning to soak up all
the oxygen in the markets. Just five companies now represent a quarter of all the value of the S&P 500
and we're seeing tremendous increase in market capitalization. They have absolutely accelerated
the pandemic they have gained power they have increased their market capitalization.
Think about this one company Apple is worth more than the hundred biggest companies in the
United Kingdom combined so essentially we have one firm that is bigger than the biggest companies
in a large economy. Now why is this bad? Is big necessarily bad? In and among itself being big
isn't necessarily bad but what we've seen is when companies become this dominant the sectors therein
become less innovative or they stop creating new businesses and birthing new jobs. In Brazil and
the U.S. the primary job creators are small and medium-sized businesses and there are fewer small
businesses being started in these growth sectors because they are dominated by a monopoly or duopoly
and it is difficult for them to get funded. People don't want to fund an e-commerce company or a
search engine or a social media company. There's been no new social media company launched in the
U.S. of any real size since 2011 with Pinterest so as you can see the sectors that these monopolies
dominate tend to have fewer startups and begin to lose job creation whereas sectors that don't have
a monopoly or duopoly don't have this concentration of power tend to birth more new companies and
create more new jobs more new businesses more innovation and more tax revenue. Let's talk about
Amazon. We have seen retail have a difficult year but it is beginning to rebound. COVID-19 has been
an accelerant if you will for e-commerce. In the U.S. approximately 17 percent of all retail was
done through digital channels in March of 2020. Within eight weeks after the outbreak of COVID it
leapt to 27 percent. It had been growing approximately one percent a year so what you had was a
decade of acceleration just in about eight weeks. You've also registered the same types of acceleration
across mobile and e-commerce in Latin America. We've seen a dramatic catching up on e-commerce
and adoption of mobile especially in Brazil which seems to be accelerating even faster and we've
seen that Amazon however has been somewhat stunted in Brazil. I don't know if it's regulation
or bureaucracy in the supply chain but Amazon so far hasn't been a disruptive force in Brazil.
I wouldn't take that as comfort though because it does look as if Amazon is slowly but surely
starting to turn its sights on Amazon. In the U.S. retail has been a difficult place to work or
invest unless you work for a company in Seattle specifically Amazon and that is retail if you took
Brazil excuse me if you took Amazon out of retail ETFs they've underperformed the market
and almost all other sectors because essentially retail in the U.S. has kind of become a story of
Amazon and the seven dwarfs. Amazon is now greater or worth more than the entire CPG industry so
think about that the industry that's producing most of our consumer products if you take the
entire industry it doesn't add up to the value that Amazon has created. What is Amazon's challenge
moving forward? They're running into a lot of big numbers and that is if they want to maintain the
trajectory of their stock price they're going to have to increase their top line revenues by almost
a quarter of a trillion dollars. Again Amazon has to find another 250 billion dollars in top line
revenue to maintain its growth. What does that mean? It means all roads lead to the same industry
and that is healthcare. Amazon doesn't maybe want to go into healthcare but they have to. This is
the largest industry in the western hemisphere it is incredibly ripe for disruption and Amazon has
all the pieces in place to disrupt healthcare. They have a wearable that measures your body mass
index they know what food you order they know what products you order they know your zip code
whether you're in a monogamous relationship and they have the appliances to begin communicating
with you and also begin gathering data. It's only a matter of time before you walk in and Alexa asks
you if you would like insurance diagnostics or if your child has a rash you hold it up to an Alexa
take a picture of it and then maybe they connect you with a pediatric dermatologist. I think Amazon
will be the fastest growing healthcare company in the world if it isn't already. The thing about a
monopoly is that when they come into a sector they can just announce they're entering and they
begin gathering the mother's milk of business and that's access to cheap capital. So Amazon can get
can take billions of dollars of market capitalization out of a sector just by announcing
that they're going into the business. It's sort of a Jedi mind trick where they can just begin
choking a competitor just by thinking ill of it. Let's talk about Apple. Apple typically trades at
multiple of earnings somewhere between 10 and 15. It is now leapt to 37. Why? Because it has moved
to subscription. Almost 20% of its revenues now come from subscription. This is a moment to pause
and that is whatever business you're in you should be contemplating pilot projects try and move out
of a transactional episodic type of business model retail consulting into a more recurring
revenue membership subscription model similar to what Amazon did with Prime. Netflix's recurring
revenue I believe Disney Plus is going to be a recurring revenue bundle if you will. Why is this
important? When you go to a recurring revenue model you begin focusing on the relationship between
the consumer and the company as opposed to putting your best minds and most capital into just getting
more people into the store if you will. It changes the dynamic where you become more product and
relationship focused. In addition the marketplace tends to value recurring revenue companies at a
multiple of revenues as opposed to a multiple of EBITDA. So my challenge to every CEO I speak with
is what pilot projects can you start to start transitioning to a recurring revenue model?
And even if it's only 1% of your business as long as that part of your business is growing faster
than the core business it begins to change the mentality and the way you think about the business
and the marketplace begins to recast your business as having the potential
to become the recurring revenue business. So that 20% of Apple's revenues that is subscription
is driving the increase in its multiple. And as you can see if you find a company that stock
price is dramatically increased or outpaced its revenue growth it's usually on the backs of a
move to a recurring revenue business model. Apple's challenge is the same challenge as Amazon and that
is they're running into the law of big numbers. They need to add a quarter of a trillion dollars.
Where will they go? I thought last year I predicted that they were going to go into education but that
doesn't appear to be happening. Where do I think Apple is going to go? Apple is going to go into
a sector that previously was only a hundred billion dollar market capitalization sector
until about two years ago and then it exploded to a seven hundred billion dollar sector. And I believe
that pie is so big now that they can't ignore it. What is that sector? It is the automobile sector
and that is I believe there is going to be a quarter of a trillion dollar event in the next
12 months and that event will be Tim Cook on stage unveiling an automobile, an electric automobile
with an Apple logo on it. I think that day will set off a transition of a quarter or a transfer
of a quarter of a trillion dollars from Tesla to Apple. I think Apple is the strongest brand in the
world. It does an amazing job with hardware and I think a lot of people will be very interested in
trialing an Apple car if you will. Facebook and Google have only gotten stronger. They used to
control 60 cents on the digital dollar. We saw an incredible decline in advertising in the U.S. and
in Brazil during COVID. It's returned and of course Google and Facebook have consolidated the market
and they now have about 80 percent. TV, free TV still dominates in Brazil but we're seeing that the
big players specifically Google and Facebook are starting to garner share and consolidate the market
with incredible growth rates around programmatic and online advertising. In addition these companies
can play offense when everyone else is playing defense. They have so much cash on hand. Any one
of these companies could buy Boeing and Airbus just with the cash they have on hand. Now we're
seeing some incredible externalities here and that is there is government overrun and that is
these companies have become so powerful. In addition consumers love these products so much
that they're seen as innovators and our leaders, our political leaders are somewhat remiss to apply
the same standards to these companies as they've applied to other industries. The result is regulatory
overrun. Two-thirds of men who joined extremist groups were done so after that group was suggested
to them, actively suggested by Facebook or Google. I'd like to think that some immunities are kicking
in and we're seeing around the world that organizations are saying we've had enough. For
example in Brazil they implemented a top line tax because they decided that their tax lawyers
were more sophisticated than your tax officials and they were sick of the massive tax avoidance.
The same top line tax has been implemented in France. In the UK they decided that Uber can no
longer circumvent minimum wage laws and we have antitrust or an antitrust movement here in the US
and in Australia there's been regulation against Facebook. I'm going to switch gears to something
that I think is an existential threat across some of our western economies. I call it the virgin
homicides. What do I mean by that? Typically when an industry is digitized and that is there's a
massive amount of innovation, new digital platforms that attracts cheap capital. There is a consolidation,
there's a lot of innovation, a lot of new players and then there's actually a concentration of power
that goes to the winner. Sort of a winner take most or winner take all. We saw it happen in media
as we referenced Google and Facebook are now 80 cents on the digital dollar. We saw it in
e-commerce. Amazon now represents in many markets 50 cents on the on the e-commerce dollar. We're
now seeing it in mating and that is more and more people are meeting online. It's now the
primary way that people meet potential mates or spouses is online. It's more through work, more
through going out, more through school. Now what's wrong with that? The problem is with digitization
you end up with again a winner take all and that is the Gini coefficient or the concentration is
incredibly strong online. What do I mean by that? If there are 100 people on a dating app,
four men, four men will get the majority of the interest from 46 of the 50 women leaving 46 men
fighting over the attention of four women. Now what is the criteria for this? This is politically
incorrect but the the data suggests this is that if a man can signal wealth online he garners a
tremendous amount or a disproportionate amount of interest. So if you live in a higher income zip
code, if you're able to express certification or college degrees, if you are dressed in expensive
clothes you get dramatically more swipes than people who aren't able to communicate that type
or express that type of wealth. Why is this a bad thing? So in the U.S. there was a study looking at
in 2008 how many men under the age of under the age of 30 had never had sex and people hear the
word sex and they start thinking a lot of different things but let's just think of sex as a key step
to establishing a relationship. Only 8 percent, only 8 percent of men or had not had not had sex
before the age of 30 in 2008. It has jumped to 28 percent. Almost one in three men in the United
States have never been intimate with a woman under the age of 30. Now why is this bad? It's not based
on values. It's not because they don't want to take that step. The reason it is bad is because the
most dangerous person in the world is a young, broke, and lonely male. The most volatile, violent
societies in the world have too many of this cohort and that is young men with very little to lose that
have very few guardrails. They are not attaching to work, they are not attaching to school, and they
are not attaching to a mate. That's not to say that young women who are lonely and can't find a job,
that that isn't a problem, but they don't typically become violent or start revolutions.
This leads to a variety of risky behavior. I think the adoption of meme stocks and to a
certain extent crypto is based on young people who are pursuing volatility because for the first time
at least in the U.S. a person at the age of 30 is no longer doing as well as their parents.
This is the basis for revolution. The central compact of any society is that you will do better
than your parents. When the majority of people, young people, aren't doing as well as the majority
of their parents, it sets the stage for volatility and an incredible embrace of risk because they just
have less to lose. This type of behavior or pent-up frustration leads to much more volatility
even in the investment markets. Now we're seeing this across protests and that is not to say that
these protests aren't righteous or the underlying movements aren't justified, but we're seeing an
increase in participation. So for example, Vietnam protests, approximately 1% of the population in
the United States had participated. It's almost 6% of the U.S. population has now participated in
a protest in the U.S. The bottom line is if you have a job or you're in school you have less time
to protest. We also see this translating to violence and that is in the U.S. we've had an
epidemic of mass shootings and the profile of mass shooters is frighteningly similar. It's young men
who are very lonely and feel totally detached socially. Now are there solutions? There are. We
need more on-ramps to a middle-class life other than a traditional bachelor of arts and a lot of
societies are beginning to prioritize and invest in vocational programs to give people the
opportunity to have a middle-class life even if they're not able to get to college. So a prediction
here, will 2021 be the best or the worst year in decades? I don't think the answer has been written.
I think it's kind of up to us. You could see us coming out of this disaster stronger than ever.
The fires in London spawned an incredible era of architecture. The end of World War II
led us to make massive investments in Japan and Germany and turn them into tremendous allies
such that it really largely kept the peace for the next 70 years. There are certain plants,
pyrophilic plants that only germinate after a fire. At the same time this does appear to be
bringing out some of the worst attributes in our tribal nature as a species. We politicize everything
from masks and vaccines and we seem to have a lack of empathy around what's going on and we seem to be
ignoring science at the cost of tremendous human suffering. So the economy has largely bounced back
because of massive intervention and stimulus. We are seeing incredible GDP growth again. Even in Brazil
it's estimated that we're going to see real significant GDP growth. We're also unfortunately
seeing some of the same acceleration of current trends around income inequality. In the U.S. just
one percent of the population garnered 90 percent of the gains post-COVID. We also have two people
in the U.S. who are now wealthier than the bottom 40 percent and we see the same thing in Brazil
where just six people have more wealth than half the nation. We're also seeing incredible income
inequality within companies whereas the CEOs and top management have seen their salaries
go up 14-fold whereas the average worker hasn't really had a raise in about 30 years.
So wages have not caught up. We've seen incredible gains in productivity. There's always a tension
between capital and labor and over the last 30 years capital quite frankly has been kicking the
crap out of labor and that delta in that line between productivity and profits is trillions of
dollars in shareholder value. The majority of that has gone back to shareholders and the top
management. So if you think about a society loosely bucketed into three cohorts consumers,
shareholders, and workers consumers are king. We now have the processing power of the space shuttle
for free in our pockets. Shareholders have done well. The NASDAQ is up five-fold since 2008.
It's workers that have had the toughest time and that is they have not seen not really seen a wage
increase in over 30 years. There are some incredibly encouraging things around a decrease in the poverty
rate specifically in the U.S. because of massive stimulus. We've seen the number of children living
in poverty decline by 60 percent. The bottom quintile of households have seen their incomes
increase by 20 or 30 percent. We're seeing it was temporary though in Brazil while the poverty
rate declined dramatically during emergency aid. Now that some of that emergency aid has ended we're
again seeing poverty rates start to escalate again. Obviously vaccines have been incredibly
important and we're seeing certain nations do a better job of getting them out and others.
Unfortunately in the U.S. vaccines have been politicized and we've seen an incredible drop
off in the number of vaccines being administered in the U.S. and then the vaccine or excuse me the
pathogen took advantage of this had time to morph had time to find new hosts times time to evolve
to new variants and we now in the U.S. as we do in Brazil have a variant that is not only more
infectious but just as virulent and in my home state of Florida we now have more children in
pediatric ICU's than there are in many European countries. There's a narrative that always evolves
that gives us comfort and one of those narratives was that this was not going to impact children
and we're finding out in the U.S. that that's just not true. I have an 11 year old you're not allowed
to get people vaccinated under the age of 12 and one of the reasons we are not in Florida is I will
not take my 11 year old back to Florida who is unvaccinated because I believe our leadership has
done such a terrible job of creating misinformation around vaccines and because so many people have
decided not to get a vaccination. This flies in the face of everything we know about truth and
about science and the bottom line is you're less likely to contract and less likely to spread
COVID-19 with a vaccine and it's just incredibly discouraging. I'm a big fan of the Game of Thrones
series and it's as if we we finally found Dragonstone something that can kill White
Walkers but we decided not to use this Dragonstone. I think this presents a tremendous opportunity
for the United States and that is we have incredible supply chain and can produce tremendous
quantities of vaccine. If you think about World War II when tyranny reigned across Europe and
threatened everywhere and it was going to threaten Latin America if Hitler had taken control of Europe
he then probably would have landed in Latin America at some point. Our supply chain basically
saved the world and that was we were able to produce more armaments. I think the similar
opportunity is here and that is we have more opportunity to flood the world with vaccine
than any other nation and I'd like to think the same generosity we demonstrated towards Japan
and Germany we could demonstrate towards India and Brazil and that is to storm the shores of
India and Brazil with vaccine and to reach out and grab the hands of our brothers and sisters
and create new strong bonds and new allies that might stand the test of time over the next several
decades. I'm going to end with a question around what is the profound opportunity coming out of
the novel coronavirus. I don't think it's economic. There's a meaningful opportunity professionally
and that is most auto races aren't one on the track they're one in the pits and that is if you
can continue to run around the track while everyone else is in the pits you're going to
win the race. Right now if you work for a company that offers you the technology and that company is
financially doing well you are healthy you are emotionally fit and you are able to work at full
capacity I think you should be working all the time. Why? My colleague at NYU Stern one of the
brightest strategy professors in the world talks about the notion of variance and that is when
there's huge variance that's where you want to invest. So for example if everybody in your
industry has great branch networks that's not where you invest but if there's huge variance
in their ability to data mine that's where you want to invest. Right now there's huge variance
in corporate Brazil and corporate America and that is a lot of people are able to work at full
productivity but a lot of people are not for different reasons. That is when you want to
work really hard. I think there's an opportunity to lap the competition if you will right now if
your company is blessed with the resources and you are emotionally financially and professionally
fit if you will. I think this is a tremendous opportunity to make progress because a lot of the
competition is stuck in the pits if you will. That is a meaningful opportunity. However, however
the profound opportunity is for the repair and cementing of key relationships. I wrote a book
on happiness because I struggle with my own happiness. My blessings are here my happiness
is here and I wanted to bring this and more in line with this. So happiness is similar to any
sport. If you want to be great at soccer you have to practice and I think if you want to be great
at happiness you have to study the concept and practice it. The key to being happy across almost
every study every ethnicity and every geography is the number of deep and meaningful relationships
you have. At work do you feel respected and admired and do you respect and admire other people?
Amongst your friends you get a sense of joy and camaraderie and do you know they know that you
feel a sense of joy and camaraderie and also across your family do you feel an intense level
of love and support and just as importantly do you know they know that they are intensely loved and
supported by you. So the profound opportunity is during a crisis is the repair and cementing of
relationships and that is people remember how you behave during a crisis. We give medals and ribbons
to our young men and women in uniform based on their ability to show grace and courage and love
during a crisis. We are in a crisis. People remember how you behave in a crisis. So three
questions and I end every presentation I'm giving. I will present over 300,000 people this year and
I end every presentation with the same three questions. Question one is this an opportunity
to pivot to becoming a caregiver for someone older in your life? A parent, an uncle, someone who is
struggling mentally or physically with the novel coronavirus. It's easy for us to expect care from
our parents. Is this that moment to pivot to being their parent if you will too? Do you have the
relationship with your siblings that you want? If you had been one of the people that was forced to
say goodbye to your sibling who was in the emergency room over FaceTime is your relationship where you
want it to be? And then finally have you made the requisite investments in friendships to maintain
those friendships or have you let perceived slights or competitiveness or other bullshit get in the
way of those friendships? The key to our happiness is the number of deep and meaningful relationships
and the novel coronavirus presents us with a tremendous opportunity if you are blessed with
health, financial security, and grace to repair and cement those relationships. A meaningful
opportunity professionally, a profound opportunity for the repair and cementing of key relationships.
Let's summarize. We are experiencing decades and days. The novel coronavirus's enduring feature will
be seen as an accelerant more than a change agent whether it's the number of people living at home,
whether it's income inequality, whether it's telehealth, whether it's dispersion of financial
markets. All the existing trends are just accelerating. An interesting question to ask yourself
take every trend professionally and personally and take it out 10 years and ask yourself are
we here right now and if so how would you change your business strategy and how would you change
your own personal approach to your own relationships? Amazon, Apple, Facebook, and Google continue to
their march. I believe that they have overrun government and are a threat to our society and
they should be broken up. We have an emerging crisis among young men who are not attaching to
work, not attaching to school, and not attaching to relationships and I believe that we are on the
precipice of what could be the best or the worst year in the last several decades but I don't think
it's an organic decision. I think it's up to us and I think the profound opportunity is to demonstrate
grace, forgiveness, and generosity during a crisis and we are in a crisis. The profound opportunity
again is to invest in and repair and cement key relationships. My name is Scott Galloway. I teach
at NYU. I'll stop right there and I'll open it up for questions and answers.
Thank you Scott. That was amazing. Thanks for your presentation. This is Fernando here. If I may
start with the question, I'm an avid listener of your podcast, the Prof. G show. The few times that
I'm able to go to the gym I always listen to it and one of your earlier predictions regarding
the big tech firms was that they need to be broken up, right? They are too powerful and you talk about
that, that they need to be separated at some sorts or there needs to be more regulation
on those companies. We've seen China going through that route in recent weeks and months
so I just wanted to see what are your thoughts regarding what China is doing and what the US
can or will do in the future with regards to regulation of the big tech firms?
Thanks for the question. I've been thinking a lot about this. Americans are some of the most,
I think we are an exceptionally innovative, generous people. We're also, our comorbidity is
our arrogance and that is we believe that the American way is so far superior we don't even
like to learn from other nations and I think there's a lot to be learned from what is going
on in China right now. China over the last 30 years has brought three quarters of a billion
people out of poverty so I'm not a fan of China. You could argue they're engaged in kind of
genocide, autocracy, but there's just no getting around it. Bringing 750 million people out of
poverty is one of the greatest accomplishments in the history of mankind so to not learn from the
Chinese is to basically decide to put your head in the sand and what can we learn? The Chinese have
looked across the Pacific at the United States and said we are not going to subvert societal
interest economic interests and they decided to essentially take some of these iconic companies
that seem to be engaged in economic or government overrun and they have severely curtailed their
power and they're talking about breaking them up. They have taken online tutoring companies
that were helping the children of rich families get into the best colleges and they have said no
more of that. They are worried about income inequality. They are worried about companies
or families building dynasties. They have decided that they are going to force video game companies
to limit the amount of time the young people spend on video games and social networks.
So when you look at what they've done essentially they have looked at the U.S. and said that the U.S.
is heading down a dangerous path of too much corporate concentration, a lack of regard for
the mental well-being of young people, and the emergence of income inequality through dynastic
wealth through education that's only accessible to the children of rich people. I think that is very
interesting and I think we should not, I'm not suggesting we adopt their kind of hard-handed
tactics, but I think it's interesting to look at China which plays the long game
and has been more successful than any nation relatively speaking economically over the last
30 years and to understand or register what they see as being the biggest mistakes in the United
States. So I think there's a lot to learn there. I personally don't think that these companies,
I think they're going to wrap their knuckles but I don't think they're going to cut their fingers
off. I personally think that these internet companies are really good investments right now.
For example, Alibaba, which is the Amazon of Asia trades at a forward price earnings multiple of
about 17 versus Amazon trades at 60 despite the fact that Alibaba is growing faster than Amazon.
So basically when you buy Alibaba you're buying Amazon for a third of the price because there's
such a chill and there's such a concern that China is going to withdraw from the capital markets
and that any investment in these companies is going to be stranded. I don't think that's the
case. I think the Chinese are effectively sent a very strong signal of these companies but they're
not going to shut them down. So I think China offers an opportunity for us to learn by seeing
how they see the U.S. I do believe the U.S. is going to break up big tech. We have a tendency
to think that it's bad for capitalism. If you look at most breakups the shareholders win. So for
example, PayPal used to be part of eBay. It's now worth dramatically more than eBay. Spends typically
work. When AT&T, our biggest telco, was broken up in the 80s here in the U.S. each of the seven
companies the baby bells that was broken up into ended up being worth more than the original AT&T
with just 10 years. So I don't think we break up these companies necessarily because they're bad
people or some sort of punishment but because breaking them up is a key component of oxygenating
the economy. So I think the breakup is coming and I think it'll be good for the stock market,
good for investors, good for job growth, good for the planet. Thank you so much. Who wants to go next?
Okay sure. So thank you for your brilliant presentation professor. I guess I've also
become a fan of your podcast and I've heard on a couple of different occasions you mention a very
interesting a bit polemic view I would say for some especially at these times in terms of what
young people should focus when they think about what to do with their lives in career-wise I would
say and I say I quote here something that I heard in your podcast, find your talent, don't find your
passion. So I personally think this is an amazing view. I've been a fan of doing that. I've been
trying to do that for my whole life but most people say I'm a bit crazy so I was very happy
to hear someone as brilliant as you say something like that. I don't know could you could you say a
bit further and share your views on this? Thanks for being kind. So at the business school we're
very fortunate we get guest speakers almost every day and generally there's two types of speakers.
Someone who is very impressive and very accomplished or a billionaire. In the U.S. we've
decided anyone that reaches a billion dollars in wealth has insight into life and they always end
their speech with what I think is just terrible advice and they say follow your passion and it's
somewhat ironic because typically the person telling you to follow your passion made their
billions in iron ore smelting or health care maintenance. Typically I think as a young person
you should be wary that anyone who tells you to follow your passion is already rich and I wanted
to be an athlete, a professional athlete growing up and I learned very quickly that that was not
where my talent lied and so I tried to find something I was good at and I think your job
as a young person is to find something you're good at and then to invest the requisite grit,
thousands of hours enduring hardship, enduring failure, enduring frustration. That's called work
and then become great at it and when you become great at something the accoutrements of being
great at it money, economic security, prestige, camaraderie, self-worth, all of those things will
make you passionate about whatever it is. Nobody grows up passionate about tax law
but the best tax lawyers in the world fly private and have a much broader selection set of mates
than they deserve which makes them passionate about tax law. So do your passions on weekends,
be a DJ, play soccer on weekends but find something that you could be the best in the world at.
That's your job. That's your job. Arthur? Hi Scott. Going back to your sector which is education,
you showed the chart between profits and wages, right? Let's face it, the majority of the world
is going to be workers, right? I mean does it mean that we have had a massive failure of educational
systems that are not able to keep up with technology and can we change that going forward?
I do think there's been a failure amongst myself and my cohorts and that is we no longer see
ourselves as, Arthur, as public servants. We see ourselves as luxury brands and that is,
so when I went to UCLA the admittance rate was 70% meaning if 100 people applied 70 got in and I had
to apply twice to get in and the cost was approximately a thousand dollars a year. This
year the admittance rate will be 9% and the cost is $35,000 a year which means that I wouldn't be
here. I'm not a humble person. I think I'm exceptionally talented but the reason I'm here
speaking to you from Nantucket and getting to do wonderful things with my life and provide economic
security for my family is because back in the 80s we used to let in unremarkable kids into college
and they let in the sons of single immigrant mothers who lived and died as secretary which
was my mother. We never had a household income more than $35,000 a year. The U.S. education
system and to a certain extent the global education system used to be about finding good people and
giving them great opportunities. In the U.S. we've now become Hermes and that is we think our job
is not to find good kids and give them great opportunities but our job is to find the top 1%
and turn them into billionaires. That's not the purpose of an economy. The key to any economy
is to give unremarkable people remarkable opportunities so I think we need to fall
back in love with the unremarkables. Harvard got 55,000 applications this year and they let in
1,400 students. This despite the fact they sit on an endowment that's the GDP of El Salvador.
They could let in 14,000 people not sacrifice any quality and they'd have the resources so the
question is well why wouldn't they? And a lot of us brag I don't know if you've done this a lot of
us brag about we say I would never get into the college I went into I went to I would never be
admitted. Well don't brag about that because that means your daughter's not getting in.
So we in public education need to fall back in love with the unremarkables and stop thinking
of ourselves as Chanel and Hermes and go back to a world where we are public servants.
The children of rich people they're the ones that don't need college. They have a great education
up until that point. They have connections. They have money. They have a safety net. They have access
to capital. It's the people we're not letting in that need college the most so we need to fall back
in love with unremarkables. We need to go back to a viewpoint that education is not a luxury brand
that we're public servants and we need to massively massively increase enrollment rates and decrease
costs through a mix of small and big tech and me and my cohorts need to be recognized that we are
not luxury brands we are public servants we have totally lost the script. Higher education in the
U.S. has become the enforcer of the caste system. It used to be an incredible upward lubricant and
we need to return to those roots. Well unfortunately our timing is coming to an end so on the name of
XP I'd like to thank you very much Scott for being here with us for your fantastic presentation for
everything you do. Hopefully we can get you here on the ground next year when this event goes back
to being live hopefully knock on wood but thank you so much. Thank you best best of wishes greetings
everybody.
Thank you Raquel and for everyone who followed us in this conversation and don't miss the next
expert's lectures because the expert is just starting.
you