We worship at the altar of innovators and billionaires. I think this perversion is best typified by the shit show
I refer to as HQ 2 where Amazon is gamified the HQ 2 process and basically
Created a game which will result in a transfer of wealth from municipalities fire districts school districts and police forces to Amazon shareholders
I believe it is a ruse. I believe they have absolutely no intention of being in any of these 18 cities
I believe this game was over before it started where will their headquarters be it's very simple
If you are the wealthiest man in the world and you're 54 and as someone who's in his 50s and is fairly economically secure
Obviously not on the same magnitude. I can tell you start measuring your life in days and weeks
I have ten more
Christmases with my youngest son. I have 35 more on this planet. I don't do pretty much anything
I don't want to do anymore
So query me this if you're the wealthiest man in the world at a hundred and sixty five billion dollars
Which means you have more options than anyone else in the world
Are you going to despite decide to spend three months a year much less three minutes in Indianapolis?
Let's again talk about human behavior
The way it usually go downs in households in terms of what's best for the welfare of the children is
Dad's an influencer and mom is the decider if you're miss Bezos again tied for number one is the wealthiest person in the world
And you endure rainy Seattle ten months a year. Are you gonna decide that you and your kids should spend more time in Toronto?
This was over before it started the Bezos have two houses one in New York one in DC
The next headquarters will be DC because the only thing in between
Amazon and one trillion and two trillion in market cap is regulation
No one is going to regulate the gentleman showing throwing out the first pitch of the 2019 Washington National Seasons
Which will be Jeffrey Bezos
You